Michael Morris



tendoaki@gmail.com



606-344-0594



linkedin.com/in/michael-morris-00b4b7118



https://mmorris-sandbox.net

Summary

I've been involved in professional web development for 19 years. I am a full stack capable developer, but much of my recent experience has been in the JavaScript sphere, particularly server side with Node is. I have extensive experience with the emerging Single-Spa framework which allows multiple popular frameworks to be used on a website at the same time, or more importantly allows older websites to be divided up into discrete chunks allowing those chunks to be updated. I know and vastly prefer Typescript to vanilla JavaScript.

I am passionate about the BDD process which provides the most value to the client of all the various testing processes out there. I this delivery process to an entire team. I taught that team, around 30 strong, how to use Cucumber with Puppeteer (Google's antecedent to Microsoft Playwright) using binding shim I wrote for them, and then shepherded the development of nearly 1000 functional tests on a code base that was being developed without automated testing before. That testing system also included a data provider mock to decouple front end development from the back end team so the front end coders could do their work regardless if the back end team had the database servers up.

I am fully versed in the construction of deployment pipelines in gitlab, and have set up continuous integration tasks in Circle CI, Travis CI and Jenkins. I thoroughly test code, usually in Cucumber-js, but I'm also familiar with Jest (I've played with Mocha, Chai and Jasmine enough to know I can be up to speed with them quickly). I have used Ansible and constructed playbooks with it.

I know jQuery, Bootstrap, and even abandoned stuff like Prototype.js. I am well versed in the process of updating software from those projects to modern ES6+ frameworks.

I have worked on PHP extensively and I have contributor credits on the Drupal project and PHPUnit.

I have worked with GoLang and C# over the years. I had a 2 year stint with Java writing Cucumber tests in the Java implementation of that framework. I've had to write Python scripts for AWS containers. Oh, yeah, and I have worked with those although not as much as I'd like to. There's very little I can't pick up quickly.

I know how to use Adobe Creative suite, Jira and participate in Agile methodology.

Outside code I play the piano and recorder flutes. Before moving to care for my parents I was active in musical theater in the Mobile AL area. I sing countertenor (highest male vocal range).

Experience



Programmer

Freelance

Sep 2016 - Present (6 years 6 months)



Jan 2018 - Jan 2023 (5 years 1 month)

Software Development Consultant

Rural Sourcing

Jan 2017 - Jan 2022 (5 years 1 month)

I am a veteran Javascript programmer who has become specialized in writing automated test code using the Cucumber framework - I have professional experience with the Java, PHP and JavaScript versions of that framework. I can also create frontend and backend code



Web Developer

Tombras

Jul 2013 - Aug 2016 (3 years 2 months)

I started at Tombras in July of 2013 and worked until last month. I was hired as a front end developer but used as both a front and back end developer, as well has having several technical director tasks given to me (Server setup, DNS routing, and other DevOps tasks).

Much of my coding focus was SEO related, putting together Wordpress sites or coding small brochure pages.

Education



University of Kentucky

Theater 1996 - 2000

Skills

Webpack • React.js • TypeScript • Software Testing • Linux • JUnit • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Python (Programming Language) • Go (Programming Language) • Development Tools